

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · FULL STACK DEVELOPER

□ (+92) 301-4239116 | 🗷 sameerwasem01@gmail.com | 🏕 sameerwasim.github.io | 🖸 sameerwasim | 🛅 sameerwasim

### **Summary**

As a Software Engineer holding a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science from the University of Punjab, I bring extensive experience in JavaScript, PHP, and Python to the table. My accomplishments include a track record of successfully building web and mobile applications, RESTful APIs, web scraping tools, and web testing tools.

#### Skills

Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python, Skills, SASS, HTML/CSS

**Databases** MySQL, MSSQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Frameworks NodeJS, NextJS, Laravel, Codeigniter, GatsbyJS, React Native, Amplify

LibrariesReactJS, BeautifulSoupToolsGit, Github Actions, Selenium

## **Work Experience**

**RipeSeed**Lahore, Pakistan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jan. 2023 - Present

- · Build and maintain cloud-based applications using React, Node, Express, Next.js, Laravel, and AWS services.
- · Write clean and testable code, collaborate with cross-functional teams, and participate in code reviews and design discussions.
- Automate the CI/CD pipeline, troubleshoot issues, and continuously improve skills and knowledge.

Wellcreator Lahore, Pakistan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER March 2020 - Dec 2022

- Develop and deploy web and mobile applications, as well as maintain associated databases
- Lead a team of developers to ensure timely project delivery and high-quality code
- · Act as a liaison between clients and the development team to ensure project requirements are met and client satisfaction is achieved.

Master Communication Lahore, Pakistan

INTERN

Nov. 2019 - Feb 2020

- Managed and maintained existing connections infrastructure.
- Configured and troubleshot network traffic to ensure optimal performance.

#### **Education**

University of Punjab

Lahore, Pakistan

**B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** 2018 - 2021

• For my final year project, I completed an art gallery project.

## **Projects**\_

CityBook citybook.pk

TECH STACK: REACT, REACT NATIVE, NODEJS, EXPRESSJS, MYSQL

Web & Mobile App

- Designed and coded Citybook's scalable and secure back-end functionality.
- · Developed the mobile app for Citybook with an intuitive user experience and optimal performance.
- · Managed the Citybook project team, completing the project on time and within budget, and deployed the application to a live environment.

List Networks listnetworks.com

TECH STACK: CODEIGNITER 4, MYSQL, JQUERY

Web App

- Developed a full-stack web application from start to finish, including designing the user interface, implementing backend functionality, and
  optimizing database performance.
- Deployed the web application to a live server, ensuring it was secure, scalable, and able to handle high traffic volumes.
- Continuously monitored and improved the web application's performance, incorporating user feedback and market trends to enhance functionality and user experience.

My Auction Sheet myauctionsheet.com

TECH STACK: REACT, NODEJS, EXPRESSJS, MYSQL

- Designed and coded My Auction Sheet's scalable and secure back-end functionality.
- · Integrated Various APIs (Google, Facebook) and Payment Methods such as Stripe, PayPal, and PayPak to ensure a smooth checkout flow.

AutoDeals.pk autodeals.pk

TECH STACK: PHP, REACT, NODEJS, EXPRESSJS, MYSQL

Web App

Web App

- Maintained and optimized the backend and database of the platform.
- Communicated with clients effectively and worked with the development team to ensure client requirements were implemented correctly.
- Managed the autodeals.pk team and conducted code reviews to maintain code quality and best practices.

inPKR inpkr.com

TECH STACK: PHP, JAVASCRIPT, MYSQL

Web App

- Developed the web application from scratch to finish, implementing backend functionality, and optimizing database performance.
- · Designed & coded Github Actions & Tests for Continuous Integration and Continuous Development.

# **Contributions & Packages**

**jazzcash-checkout** Node.js package that provides easy integration of JazzCash payment gateway.

mysql-rcm Node.js package that helps create REST API endpoints for a MySQL database using express and mysql2.

sitemap-generator A XML Sitemap generator to design dynamic sitemap for your website built using PHP.